Global Malnutrition Trends: A Power BI Analysis from 1983 to 2019. This project analyzes child malnutrition indicators using an interactive Power BI dashboard.
Understanding long-term malnutrition trends is challenging due to large and complex datasets. This project addresses the need for clear, visual, and data-driven insights.
The dataset is originally published by UNICEF, WHO, and the World Bank, and accessed through a public GitHub repository. It covers the years 1983 to 2019.
The dataset includes indicators such as stunting, underweight, wasting, income classification, and survey sample size across multiple countries.
This line chart shows year-wise trends of stunting, underweight, and wasting, highlighting an overall decline in malnutrition indicators over time.
Wasting displays higher year-to-year variation compared to other indicators, indicating sensitivity to short-term health and nutrition conditions.
This bar chart highlights the top 10 countries with the highest average stunting percentages, helping identify high-risk regions.
KPI cards summarize key metrics including average stunting, underweight, wasting, and total survey sample size.
The donut chart represents the proportional contribution of stunting, underweight, and wasting to overall child malnutrition.
The matrix visualization provides country-wise comparison using conditional formatting for better interpretability.
Conditional formatting uses red, orange, and green colors to represent high, medium, and low severity levels.
Income classification is included to analyze the relationship between economic status and malnutrition prevalence.
In conclusion, the dashboard enables quick identification of trends, high-risk countries, and severity of malnutrition indicators.
Thank you for watching. This project demonstrates how Power BI can transform complex health data into actionable insights.